<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on sleeplessCamel</title><link>https://sleeplesscamel.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on sleeplessCamel</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 13:59:31 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sleeplesscamel.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Lament to the Woods</title><link>https://sleeplesscamel.github.io/posts/hurt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 13:59:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sleeplesscamel.github.io/posts/hurt/</guid><description>&lt;p>a few weeks ago, while rewatching the remains of On Air With AIB, i ended up watching
Karunesh Talwar&amp;rsquo;s rendition of &lt;em>Sun Raha Hai Na Tu&lt;/em>, where he sings a rather poignant
ballad on dwindling numbers of the &lt;strong>Great Indian Bustard&lt;/strong>. You can see it
&lt;a
 href="https://youtu.be/fyJmmsD4lys?si=m69vl54NbK-TtL3C&amp;amp;t=242"
 
 target="_blank" rel="noopener"
 
 
>here&lt;/a>
. this was 2015.
fucking 2015. i actually tried to look up what was the current state of these birds.
we had about 250 individuals in 2011 which got down to 150 by 2018, and just hear this,
there has been literally no census since then.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Banshees of Inisherin</title><link>https://sleeplesscamel.github.io/posts/inisherin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 08:27:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sleeplesscamel.github.io/posts/inisherin/</guid><description>&lt;p>this got a bit too topical.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;figure>
 &lt;img
 src="https://sleeplesscamel.github.io/images/post_pics/inisherin/k8azyHZ8T7bQeUh9GPnSfc5zA6.jpg"
 
 
 
 loading="lazy"
 alt="let&amp;rsquo;s call it quits"
 
 />
 
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>it&amp;rsquo;s not the best feeling when you realise you have been in the shoes of the both
asshole protagonists. i have been the one who abruptly ended friendships, and
i&amp;rsquo;ve been on the end of continuously nagging someone that they told me to fuck off.
and mind you, i deserved the latter every single time it happened.&lt;/p>

&lt;h2 id="retrospective">retrospective &lt;a class="heading-anchor" href="#retrospective" aria-hidden="true">#&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>this isn&amp;rsquo;t a film review as much it&amp;rsquo;s an retrospective of my own relationships with
people. truth be told, im not good at those. it&amp;rsquo;a shame, because although i proclaim
that i can live by myself, that being alone is my ground state, that i will be happy
doing that, despite all this, there&amp;rsquo;s this innate desire to still part of a group. a
sense of belonging. but that is not a luxury, is it? how can one take this audacious
stance of being proud by ignoring others on his own whims and then desire contact all of
a sudden. it does not work like that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uma</title><link>https://sleeplesscamel.github.io/posts/uma/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 18:37:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sleeplesscamel.github.io/posts/uma/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>film starts with For all fathers, wherever they are. something tells me maybe im not ready for this one guys&lt;/li>
&lt;li>she&amp;rsquo;s literally me&lt;/li>
&lt;li>fuck, i can&amp;rsquo;t be a doctor like that&lt;/li>
&lt;li>a man obsessed with his work oblivious to the treasure he has in his life in the form of his daughter and wife. this is actually so great, with the way the whole background story is being set-up through a montage over a melancholic song.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>this is my only second Bengali film but i appreciate this so much that the creators do not consider the audience smooth-brained and don&amp;rsquo;t spoonfed every plot point through dialogue&lt;/li>
&lt;li>we only remember the importance of something or someone when they are no longer there. may this be a lesson to cherish what you have right now.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lmao this Barun guy and his wife are just great friends&lt;/li>
&lt;li>okay okay okay are those real bengali directors cameos lmao&lt;/li>
&lt;li>holy shit i love this film&amp;rsquo;s humor lmao. this director is just going full-on liberal on Himu&amp;rsquo;s gang&lt;/li>
&lt;li>we have to keep telling the story, as storytellers, with all the life we have&lt;/li>
&lt;li>TIL about kashful&lt;/li>
&lt;li>nooooo google excel strikes here again ðŸ˜­&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;figure>
 &lt;img
 src="https://sleeplesscamel.github.io/images/post_pics/uma/Screenshot%20from%202024-10-11%2018-41-18.png"
 
 
 
 loading="lazy"
 alt="dracula sir spotted"
 
 />
 
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Goat</title><link>https://sleeplesscamel.github.io/posts/goat/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 11:23:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sleeplesscamel.github.io/posts/goat/</guid><description>&lt;p>i hate goats. i hope they all die.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>this was me, several moons ago. never doing that again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;figure>
 &lt;img
 src="https://sleeplesscamel.github.io/images/post_pics/goat/goat.jpg"
 
 
 
 loading="lazy"
 alt="circa 2003, colorized"
 
 />
 
&lt;/figure>

&lt;figure>
 &lt;img
 src="https://sleeplesscamel.github.io/images/post_pics/goat/goat.gif"
 
 
 
 loading="lazy"
 alt="animated"
 
 />
 
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fuck goats. Fucking rectangle pupiled monsters.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dracula Sir</title><link>https://sleeplesscamel.github.io/posts/dracula-sir/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 02:27:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sleeplesscamel.github.io/posts/dracula-sir/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>oh he combs so much, im uncomfortable. few moments later scares the kid with unkempt hair and dracula snare lol&lt;/li>
&lt;li>i absolutely love the fact that even the songs are subtitled ðŸ¥¹, and what a lovely song. the lyrics man. at this point im sure it&amp;rsquo;s just hindi songs which have shitty lyrics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>bengalis and their attics. i am in love with this aesthetic and im almost on the verge of having nostalgia for something i never experienced myself&lt;/li>
&lt;li>it snows in Kolkata (and electric guitar plays, just why and how this film&amp;rsquo;s soundtrack is so good lol)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Raktim or à¦°à¦•à§à¦¤à¦¿à¦®, the word for red, the red of the blood, name for someone who longs for it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the parallels. so many parallels. ï¼°ï¼¡ï¼²ï¼¡ï¼¬ï¼¬ï¼¥ï¼¬ï¼³.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>in stories where the line between reality and someone&amp;rsquo;s imagination is blurred, the viewer themselves are required to detach from the world and immerse in the story.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>and the ending lol where the psychiatrist asks Raktim which character now he will be in his story and he is now suddenly the dead husband ðŸ˜­&lt;/li>
&lt;li>also the tear gas callback ðŸ¥¹ (yes this emoji was also met with tear gas)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>again, i am so impressed with the lyrics (everything else about the songs, but the lyrics especially). they&amp;rsquo;re so many lines that just straight up foreshadow the events. so poetic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>i think at one point the doctors tells Raktim to write again. he rode the books on Naxalbari uprising, probably influence from his father as he got them from him. and of course, &amp;ldquo;Kolkata&amp;rsquo;s Dracula&amp;rdquo; by some Haridas Bandyopadhyay. I wanted this to be a real book&lt;/li>
&lt;li>i like stories like these. life of pi comes to my mind. there&amp;rsquo;s one version which is rational, plausible, logical. but it&amp;rsquo;s lame. the charm lies in the fantastical. a story of a revolutionary, torn between love and war, reincarnated to complete his revenge and redeem himself. what really happened is secondary, what really matters is what the viewer chooses to believe in&lt;/li>
&lt;li>i have probably many many more things to say, but my eyes keep closing and i have to somehow survive till lunch, so the words aren&amp;rsquo;t really coming out right now. i would love to talk about the film more later in person lol&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>